Now let's talk about queues.
现在，让我们来谈谈队列
So, a queue has some similarities with a stack.
队列与堆栈有着诸多相似点
But in a fundamental way is different.
但是，在一个重要的方面，他们是极其不同的
So it's an abstract data type and these are the operations that it has.
队列是一种抽象数据类型，它可以进行多种操作
You can Enqueue a key, it adds the key to the collection.
当你入队(Enqueue)一个元素（key）,队列将会添加这个键
And then when you Dequeue, that gives you back a key and removes it from the queue.
当你进行删除操作（Dequeue），当前队列将会返回一个元素（Key）并且将其从队列中去除
It removes and returns the least recently added key,
这个被返回并且去除的键，是最早添加的那一个。
rather than in the case of a stack, the most recently added key.
而不是像一个堆栈，堆栈的删除操作是在最近添加的元素（Key）上进行的
So that's the fundamental difference.
所以说，那就是队列和堆栈最本质的不同
If you think about queues as like queuing up in line or
如果你将队列想象成在一个队伍里排队
waiting in line, this is a first come first serve situation.
你就会明白队列遵循的是先来先服务的原则
So the longer you've been waiting in line, so
所以，你在队伍里等待得越久
the longest person waiting in line is the next person to be served.
就像在队伍里等待时间最长的那个人，将会是下一个被服务的人
Makes sense.
为了便于理解
So you can imagine if you had a grocery store that had
你可想象你有一个杂货店
a stack that it used for serving people, people would be pretty annoyed, right?
如果杂货店以堆栈的形式服务客人，客人将会变得相当恼怒，对吗？
Because the person who'd just arrived,
因为（你想想），那个刚刚到达的人
you've been waiting in line ten minutes, a person just arrives,
你已经排了十分钟的队，一个刚刚到达的人
they get served before you do, that would not make you happy.
他们比你还早得到服务，你不会乐意看到这件事的
So, queues are very useful for instance, for things like servers.
所以，队列是十分有用的，比如说对于服务者
Where you've got a bunch of operations coming in and
当一大堆操作开始进行
you want to service the one that's been waiting the longest.
服务者会优先服务等待最久的那个请求
The other operation is you can find out whether the queue is empty or not.
队列可以进行的其他操作诸如你可以检查队列是否为空
So these are often called FIFO, first in, first out,
队列的这些特性可以称之为FIFO，先进，先出
and this distinguishes them from stacks which are LIFO.
这一原则明显区分于堆栈的LIFO（后进先出）
Last in, first out.
后买进的先卖出
First in first out, or first come first serve, same thing.
先进先出，或者说，先来先服务
How can you implement a queue?
那么，如何实现一个队列呢？
Well, one way is with a linked list, where you have a head and a tail pointer.
一种方式是通过一个拥有头指针和尾指针的链表实现
So let's say we start out with an empty linked list.
让我们从一个空链表开始
We can go ahead and Enqueue, and what we're going to do basically in an Enqueue,
接着，执行入队（Enqueue）操作。在入队操作里
is we are going to push to the back of the linked list, so
我们要做的是将元素（Key）插入到队列的尾部
that's how we'll implement Enqueue.
这就是我们如何实现一个入队操作
So here, we Enqueue (a), it's now at the back of the linked list.
你可以看到，当我们对a进行入队操作，a已经在链表的尾部
If we Enqueue (b), it's going to be then added, again,
如果我们对b进行入队操作，b也将会被添加到队列里
at the end of the linked list.
在链表的尾部位置
Is it empty? No.
链表是空的吗？答案显然是否定的
How do we know it's not empty?
我们怎么知道队列是否为空的呢？
Well the simplest thing is we would just call to the underlying list implementation
最简单的做法，我们将仅仅求助于链表的底层实现方式
and say hey, list are you empty?
看看链表是否为空
It would say no.
链表不为空
And so empty for the queue is no.
也就意味着队列不为空
We know it's really happening just by checking whether the head is nil or not.
检验链表是否为空，要做的，仅仅是检验其头指针是否为空
If we Enqueue(c) then, again it goes to the tail of the list.
如果我们将c进行入队操作，c将被插入链表的尾部
And if I now Dequeue, which one is going to be removed?
如果我现在进行出队（Dequeue）操作，哪一项会被去除呢？
Again this is not a stack, in a stack c would be removed.
再一次说明，这不是一个堆栈，在堆栈里，c会被去除
In our case, (a) is going to be removed because it's been there longest.
在这个例子里，a将被去除，因为a在队伍里待得最久
That's just an implementation of popping from the front.
这就是从队首去除元素的实现
So that would return (a).
所以，这一操作将返回a
We can now do some more Enqueueing, Enqueue(d), Enqueue(e),
现在，我们可以进行一些更多的入队操作，将d入队，将e入队
Enqueue(f), and now if we start Dequeueing, we Dequeue from the front.
将f入队，好了，我们停止入队操作，开始从队首进行出队操作
So Dequeuing (b), Dequeuing (c), Dequeuing (d), Dequeuing (e), and
将b出队，将c出队，将d出对抗，将e出队
finally Dequeuing (f).
最后，将f出队
If we ask whether the queue is empty now, the answer is yes.
现在如果我们查询队列是否为空，答案是yes
Again, because the head is nil.
需要注意的是，我们判断的依据是，头指针是空指针
So Enqueue uses list's PushBack call and Dequeue uses both the list's
入队操作需要使用链表的PushBack操作，出队操作需要使用到链表的
TopFront to get the front element as well as PopFront to remove that front element.
TopFront操作去获得队首的元素，出队操作还需要链表的PopFront操作去删除队首元素
And Empty just uses the list's Empty method.
判定队列是否为空仅仅也是使用了链表的Empty方法
What about with an array?
如果用一个数组实现呢？
We could think of doing something similar.
可以预见，做法是相似的
That is, we could add at the end and then pop from the front.
也就是说，我们可以在尾部添加，在头部弹出并删除元素
But you can imagine, so,
你可以自己想象一下
we said the front of the array is the beginning of the queue.
我们所说的数组头部，也就是队列的队首
Then enqeueing is easy, but dequeuing would be an expensive O(n) operation.
入队操作很容易，但是出队（Dequeue）操作的代价高达O(n)
And we want enqeueing to be O(1).
我们想要实现O（1）复杂度的出队操作
We can do that, in a fashion I'll show you right now which is basically
我们可以做到，以一种不那么完美的方式，我将向你演示，这种方式
keeping track of sort of the array as a circular array.
通过追踪某种环形数组实现
So we're going to go ahead and Enqeue (a), and we have a write index.
让我们继续，对a进行入队操作，现在我们有了写入的编号地址
And the write index tells us where the next Enqueue operation should happen.
写入的编号告诉我们，下一个入队操作应该在哪里发生
And the read tells us where the next Dequeue operation should happen.
读入的编号则告诉我们下一个出队操作应该在哪里进行
So we Enqueue a, we Enqueue b, and now update our write index.
所以，我们将a入队，将b入队，现在我们更新写入编号
If we ask whether we're empty?
如果我们查询队列是否为空？
No, we're not empty because read is not equal to write.
不为空，因为读入的编号和写入的编号不相等
That is we have something to Dequeue that has been Enqueued.
那就是说，队列中还有已经入队的元素没有出队
So Empty would be false.
Empty方法也就返回false
We Enqueue (c), we Dequeue, again we're going to Dequeue (a), so
我们对c进行入队操作，然后出队，再次说明，我们出队的对象是a
we Dequeue from the read index.
我们出队的操作用过读入编号实现
So we basically read what's at the read index and then increment the read index.
所以，我们所做的，不过是，读取在读入编号的元素，并且增加读入编号
If we now Dequeue again, we read what's at the read index which is (b) and
如果我们再次进行出队操作，我们读取的将是在读入编号位置的b，接着
we increment the read index.
我们增加原有的读入编号
Now we will do some more Enqueueing.
现在，我们可以做一些更多地入队操作
Notice at this point that when we Enqueue(d), the write index is 4,
需要注意的是，这时当我们将d入队时，写入的编号将是4
that's the next place we're going to Enqueue(e), which will have us write
下一次我们将e入队
to the index 4 and then the write index wraps back around to the initial element.
e将被放入编号为4的位置，而写入编号将回到最初的位置
And, here it's important to note we're using zero based indexing with this array
一个需要注意的地方是，这个数组中，我们使用的编号方式是从0开始的
because of the fact that the first element is zero.
由于第一个元素的编号就是0
We Enqueue again, Enqueue (f), and
我们再次进行入队操作，将f入队
now if we try Enqueue (g), it's not going to allow us to do that.
现在，如果我们尝试将g入队，那将是不被允许的
So that will be an error.
如果进行了，会是一个错误
The reason it would be an error, is if we did Enqueue(g), the read and
错误的原因是，如果要这么做
the write index would be both be 2.
读入编好和写入编号将都变成2
And it would be hard to distinguish read and write index 2 because the queue is
那将很难区分队列是已经满了，又或者
full, or read and write index both 2 because the queue is empty.
是队列是空的
So therefore, we have a buffer of at least one element that can't be written to,
因此，我们设置一个至少一个元素的无法写入的缓冲区域
to make sure read and write are separate and
以确保读和写是分离的
distinct if the queue's not empty.
以及能够判断队列是否为空
Now we'll Dequeue, so we'll Dequeue (c), basically reading from
现在，我们将进行出队操作，所以，我们将c出队，需要做的，不过是
the read index and updating it.
从读入编号的位置读取元素，然后更新读入编号
Dequeue (d), read from the read index and update it.
将d出队，从读入编号的位置读取元素，然后更新读入编号
Dequeue (e) and here again, the read index wraps around back to 0.
将e出队，再一次地，从读入编号的位置读取元素，然后更新读入编号
And now finally, we do our final Dequeue and now the read and
最后，我们进行最后一次出队操作，现在，读入编号和
write index are both 1.
写入编号都是1
Which means if we ask whether Dequeue is empty, the answer is yes, it is empty.
也就意味着如果我们查询队列是否为空，回答将会是yes
So what we see here is that the cost for doing a Dequeue and
现在，我们可以看到，在这种方式下，出队和入队的操作
an Enqueue, as well of course as Empty, are all O(1) operations this way.
以及查询队列是否为空的代价都是O(1)
So we can use either a linked list,
我们也可以用链表实现
although we have to have a tail pointer, so that PushBack is cheap, or an array.
尽管我们必须保持一个尾部指针，以便PushBack操作可以方便进行
Each of the operations is O(1).
每一个操作的代价都是O(1)
One distinction between the array and the linked list implementation, is
用数组实现和用链表实现的不同之处在于
that in the array implementation, we have a maximum size that the queue can grow to.
在数组实现方式里，我们有一个队列所能达到的最大容量
So it's bounded.
也就是说，数组实现的队列是有界限的
Maybe you want that in which case it's fine, but if you don't know a priori
也许你喜欢用这种方式进行，那很好。但是，如果你都不知道
how long the queue you need is going to be an array is a bad choice.
你的队列要使用多久，数组实现会是个坏主意
And any amount that is unused is wasted space.
还有一点，任何没使用的空间都是浪费掉了
In a queue that's implemented with a linked list,
在一个链表实现的队列里
it can get arbitrarily large as long as there's available memory.
队列的容量可以变得任意大，只要还有足够的存储空间
The downside is, every element you have to pay for another pointer.
The downside is, every element you have to pay for another pointer.